Guide to the John Ewart Wallace Sterling, Chancellor of Stanford University, Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
John Ewart Wallace Sterling, chancellor of Stanford University, papers
circa 1950-1985
SC0333
Sterling, J. E. Wallace, (John Ewart Wallace), 1906-1985
70 Linear feet
Personal and professional correspondence, research notes, teaching notes, appointment books, day-books, and ephemera regarding his activites as Chancellor and as a professional historian. Additional files regarding the American Revolution Bi-Centennial Commission, the Huntington Library, and the Canadian American Association of Northern California, are included.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
Gift of the Sterling family and transfer from Office of the Chancellor, Stanford University, 1985.
Information about Access
The materials are open for research use.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
J. E. Wallace Sterling, 1906-1985, served as Stanford University's fifth president from 1949 to 1968, the University's greatest period of expansion. His contributions as Chancellor, from 1968-1985, were equally impressive. He served on the Stanford Board of Trustees from 1969 to 1975, and from 1972 to 1977 was national co-chairman of the $300 million Campaign for Stanford. In 1978, he received Stanford University's highest honor, the "Degree of Uncommon Man." During this period, Sterling also served as chairman of the American Bicentennial Caommission, and as founding president and chairman of the national advisory board of the Filoli Center in Woodside, California, an historic property of the National Trust for Historic Preservation. He received honorary degrees form institutions in this country and abroad, including in 1976 an honorary knighthood from Queen Elizabeth II in honor of his contributions to education and his scholarship in British history.
Description of the Collection
Personal and professional correspondence, research notes, teaching notes, appointment books, day-books, and ephemera regarding his activites as Chancellor and as a professional historian. Additional files regarding the American Revolution Bi-Centennial Commission, the Huntington Library, and the Canadian American Association of Northern California, are included.
Access Terms
American Revolution Bicentennial Commission.; Canadian American Association of Northern California.; Henry E. Huntington Library and Art Gallery..; Huntington Library and Art Gallery, San Marino, Calif.; Stanford University. Board of Trustees.; Stanford University. Chancellor's Office.; Sterling, J. E. Wallace, (John Ewart Wallace), 1906-1985; Stanford University--Administration.; Universities and colleges--Administration.
Collection Contents
- Papers, Series 1
  - Administrative records
    - Weekly Appointment Book (Secretary), 1949 (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - Weekly Appointment Book (Secretary), 1950 (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - Weekly Appointment Book (Secretary), 1951 (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - Weekly Appointment Book (Secretary), 1952 (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - Weekly Appointment Book (Secretary), 1953 (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - Weekly Appointment Book (Secretary), 1954 (Box 23, Folder 6)
    - Weekly Appointment Book (Secretary), 1955 (Box 23, Folder 7)
    - Weekly Appointment Book (Secretary), 1956 (Box 23, Folder 8)
    - Weekly Appointment Book (Secretary), 1957 (Box 23, Folder 9)
    - Weekly Appointment Book (Secretary), 1958 (Box 23, Folder 10)
    - Weekly Appointment Book (Secretary), 1959 (Box 23, Folder 11)
    - Weekly Appointment Book (Secretary), 1960 (Box 23, Folder 12)
    - Weekly Appointment Book (Secretary), 1961 (Box 23, Folder 13)
    - Weekly Appointment Book (Secretary), 1962 (Box 23, Folder 14)
    - Weekly Appointment Book (Secretary), 1963 (Box 23, Folder 15)
    - Weekly Appointment Book (Secretary), 1964 (Box 23, Folder 16)
    - Weekly Appointment Book (Secretary), 1965 (Box 23, Folder 17)
    - Weekly Appointment Book (Secretary), 1966 (Box 23, Folder 18)
    - Weekly Appointment Book (Secretary), 1967 (Box 23, Folder 19)
    - Weekly Appointment Book (Secretary), 1968 (Box 23, Folder 20)
    - Weekly Appointment Book (Secretary), 1969 (Box 23, Folder 21)
    - Weekly Appointment Book (Secretary), 1970 (Box 23, Folder 22)
    - Weekly Appointment Book (Secretary), 1971 (Box 23, Folder 23)
    - Weekly Appointment Book (Secretary), 1972 (Box 23, Folder 24)
    - Weekly Appointment Book (Secretary), 1973 (Box 23, Folder 25)
    - Weekly Appointment Book (Secretary), 1974 (Box 23, Folder 26)
    - Weekly Appointment Book (Secretary), 1975 (Box 23, Folder 27)
    - Tulane University Board of Visitors, 1969 (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - Tulane University Board of Visitors, 1968 (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - Tulane University Board of Visitors, 1966-1967 (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - Tulane University Board of Visitors, 1961-1965 (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - Tulane University Board of Visitors, 1970 (Box 24, Folder 5)
    - Tulane University Board of Visitors, 1971 (Box 24, Folder 6)
    - Tulane University Board of Visitors, 1972-1973 (Box 24, Folder 7)
    - Various Letters with Tulane, 1973-1979 (Box 24, Folder 8)
    - Canadian-American Association of Northern California, 1967-1978 (Box 24, Folder 9)
    - Canadian-American Committee, 1971-1972 (Box 24, Folder 10)
    - Canadian-American Committee, 1970-1971 (Box 24, Folder 11)
    - Canadian-American Committee, 1969-1970 (Box 24, Folder 12)
    - Canadian-American Committee, 1968-1969 (Box 24, Folder 13)
    - Canadian-American Committee, 1967-1968 (Box 24, Folder 14)
    - Canadian-American Committee, 1966-1967 (Box 24, Folder 15)
    - Canadian-American Committee, 1965-1966 (Box 24, Folder 16)
    - Canadian-American Committee, 1964-1965 (Box 24, Folder 17)
    - Canadian-American Committee, 1963-1964 (Box 24, Folder 18)
    - Canadian-American Committee, 1962-1963 (Box 24, Folder 19)
    - Canadian-American Committee, 1961-1962 (Box 24, Folder 20)
    - Canadian-American Committee, 1960-1961 (Box 24, Folder 21)
    - Canadian-American Committee, 1959-1960 (Box 24, Folder 22)
    - Canadian-American Committee, 1958-1959 (Box 24, Folder 23)
    - Canadian-American Committee, 1956-1958 (Box 24, Folder 24)
    - Toward a More Realistic Appraisal of the Automotive Agreement; A Statement by the Canadian-American Committee, 1970 May 15 (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - The Arctic: Economic Development, Pollution Control, and Sovereignty, 1970 Feb. (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - North American Agriculture in a New World, 1969 Oct. (Box 25, Folder 3)
    - Chapter III: Growing World Food Needs and North American Agriculture, 1969 Sept. (Box 25, Folder 4)
    - Chapter IV: Canadian-American Issues Over Wheat, undated (Box 25, Folder 5)
    - Letter from Miller to Sterling, 1969 Oct. 29 (Box 25, Folder 6)
    - Memorandum: Advance Consideration of a Study for the Toronto Meeting, 1969 Sept. 25 (Box 25, Folder 7)
    - Memorandum/North American Agriculture in a New World, 1969 Sept. 18 (Box 25, Folder 8)
    - Memorandum: M-90, The United States-Canadian Defense Partnership, 1969 Sept. 15 (Box 25, Folder 9)
    - Memorandum: M-89, The Growth and Changing Composition of Canada-U.S. Trade, 1969 April 8 (Box 25, Folder 10)
    - Constructive Alternatives to the Proposals for U.S. import Quotas, 1967 Dec. (Box 25, Folder 11)
    - The Multinational Corporation, 1967 Oct. (Box 25, Folder 12)
    - An Evaluation of the Canada-U.S. Automotive Agreement Project Paper, 1967 Oct. (Box 25, Folder 13)
    - U.S. Political and Cultural Influence on Canada, A Project paper, 1967 Sept. (Box 25, Folder 14)
    - U.S. Canadian Free Trade: The Potential Impact on the Canadian Economy, 1967 March (Box 25, Folder 15)
    - U.S. Programs for the Restraint of Private Capital Outflow, 1963-1967, 1967 Mar (Box 25, Folder 16)
    - Canada and the U.S. balance of Payments (A Project Paper), 1967 March (Box 25, Folder 17)
    - Movements of U.S. Private Capital, 1950-1966, 1967 Feb (Box 25, Folder 18)
    - Political and Cultural Aspects of Canadian-American Relations: A Selected Bibliography, 1966 September (Box 25, Folder 19)
    - Energy in Canadian-American Relations, 1965 Sept. 15 (Box 25, Folder 20)
    - Fresh Water in a Canadian-American Context, 1965 Sept. (Box 25, Folder 21)
    - A Summary of Location Pressures Which Would Exist in a Canada-U.S. Free Trade Area, 1964 Sept. 8 (Box 25, Folder 22)
    - Institutional Arrangements Between Canada and the United States, 1963 Sept. 11 (Box 25, Folder 23)
    - Action on the Columbia, 1963 Sept. 11 (Box 25, Folder 24)
    - Towards an International Grain Agreement, 1963 Sept. 12 (Box 25, Folder 25)
    - Make or Break in Geneva, 1963 June 5 (Box 25, Folder 26)
    - The U.S. Softwood Lumber Situation in a Canadian-American Perspective, 1962 Oct. 8 (Box 25, Folder 27)
    - U.S. Canadian Social and Cultural Relations, 1959 April (Box 25, Folder 28)
    - Uranium and Canada-United States Relations, 1959 Oct. (Box 25, Folder 29)
    - Trading Blocs: Implications for Canada and the United States, 1959 Oct. (Box 25, Folder 30)
    - A Canad-United States Trade Area, 1960 March (Box 25, Folder 31)
    - Whither Canadian-American Commercial Relations?, undated (Box 25, Folder 32)
    - The Dominant Supplier Authority in the U.S. Trade Expansion Act, 1963 March (Box 25, Folder 33)
    - A Model Plan for a Canada-United States Free-Trade Area, 1963 Sept. 2 (Box 25, Folder 34)
    - Memorandum: Several Immigration and Nationality Questions that have Evoked Interest in Canada, 1969 Sept. 29 (Box 25, Folder 35)
    - United States Capital in Canadian Development, 1967 March (Box 25, Folder 36)
    - A Proposed Statement by the Canadian-American Committee on A New Trade Strategy for Canada and the United States, 1966 March 10 (Box 25, Folder 37)
    - Power Exports and Canadian-American Relations, 1961 Sept. 1 (Box 25, Folder 38)
    - Summary of the Report of the Canadian Royal Commission on Publications, 1961 Sept. 1 (Box 25, Folder 39)
    - Why is Columbia River Development Stalled?, 1961 Sept. 1 (Box 25, Folder 40)
    - Canadian-American Relations, 1961 Sept. 1 (Box 25, Folder 41)
    - The Defense Production/Development Sharing Program Between Canada and the United States, 1961 Sept. 11 (Box 25, Folder 42)
    - Non-Merchandise Trade Transactions Between Canada and the United States, 1961 Sept. 15 (Box 25, Folder 43)
    - The Six, Seven, and the United States, 1960 Nov. (Box 25, Folder 44)
    - Cultural Relations Between Canada and the United States, 1960 Nov. (Box 25, Folder 45)
    - The Committee's Research Program: The Past Three years and the Future, 1960 Nov. (Box 25, Folder 46)
    - Status of the Project on Basic Resources in North America, 1959 June (Box 25, Folder 47)
    - A View if the Future Shape of U.S. Trade Policy, 1969 Jan. 11 (Box 25, Folder 48)
    - Canada's Future Prospects and Some Present Difficulties, 1958 Feb. 7 (Box 25, Folder 49)
    - Appleseed, 1958 Jan. 23 (Box 25, Folder 50)
    - Canadian-American Commercial Relations, 1958 May (Box 25, Folder 51)
    - Energy Transfers and their Impact Upon Canadian- United States Relations, 1958 May (Box 25, Folder 52)
    - Potentialities of a Survey of Basic Resources in North America, 1958 May (Box 25, Folder 53)
    - A Statement of Canadian-American Commercial Policy, 1958 May (Box 25, Folder 54)
    - Statement by the Honorable Livingston T. merchant United States Ambassador to Canada Before the Senate Foreign Relations Committee on United States Relations with Canada, 1958 May 16 (Box 25, Folder 55)
    - Relations Between the United States and Canada, 1958 June 25 (Box 25, Folder 56)
    - Oil, Canadian-American Relations and the Montreal Market Question, 1958 Sept. (Box 25, Folder 57)
    - Canadian-American Commercial Relations, undated (Box 25, Folder 58)
    - Northern Economic Frontiers-Alaska, Yukon, Northwest Territories, 1958 Oct. (Box 25, Folder 59)
    - Domestic Versus Foreign Financing in Canada, 1958 Sept. (Box 25, Folder 60)
    - New Horizons in U.S.-Canadian Relationships, 1958 Nov. 14 (Box 25, Folder 61)
    - Terms of Reference for a Study of Policies and Practices of U.S. Subsidiaries in Canada, 1959 May (Box 25, Folder 62)
    - Barriers to Trade Between Canada and the United States, 1959 May (Box 25, Folder 63)
    - The European Common Market: Possible Implications for Canada and the United States, 1959 May (Box 25, Folder 64)
    - Canada's Experience with Fixed and Floating Exchange Rates in a North American Capital Market, 1971 March (Box 25, Folder 65)
    - Los Angeles, 1982-1984 (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - New York, 1979 Jan.-Feb. (Box 26, Folder 2)
    - New York/Paris/Venice, 1980 May (Box 26, Folder 3)
    - Australia, 1979 Oct. (Box 26, Folder 4)
    - New York/Barbados, 1979 Feb. (Box 26, Folder 5)
    - England, 1977 (Box 26, Folder 6)
    - London-France-Toronto, 1977 (Box 26, Folder 7)
    - Mexico, 1977 Feb. 25-March 6 (Box 26, Folder 8)
    - China, 1976 Oct. (Box 26, Folder 9)
    - Los Angeles/Santa Barbara Trip, 1975 Feb. 9-12 (Box 26, Folder 10)
    - New York Trip, 1974 Oct. 21-24 (Box 26, Folder 11)
    - Europe, 1974 (Box 26, Folder 12)
    - Los Angeles Trip, 1974 Jan. 28-30 (Box 26, Folder 13)
    - Du Lunch, 1974 (Box 26, Folder 14)
    - Los Angeles, 1973 Dec. 19-20 (Box 26, Folder 15)
    - New York Trip, 1973 Dec. 6 (Box 26, Folder 16)
    - Los Angeles, 1973 Nov. 14-16 (Box 26, Folder 17)
    - Seattle/Portland, 1973 Nov. 4-7 (Box 26, Folder 18)
    - Europe (cancelled), 1973 (Box 26, Folder 19)
    - Los Angeles, 1973 March 20-22 (Box 26, Folder 20)
    - Los Angeles, 1973 Feb. 1 (Box 26, Folder 21)
    - Houston, 1973 Jan. 24 (Box 26, Folder 22)
    - Los Angeles Trip, 1972 Nov. 28-30 (Box 26, Folder 23)
    - Phoenix, 1972 Nov. 20 (Box 26, Folder 24)
    - Calgary, Atlan., 1972 Sept. 26-28 (Box 26, Folder 25)
    - New York, 1972 June 22 (Box 26, Folder 26)
    - France/England, 1972 (Box 26, Folder 27)
    - New York/Atlanta Trip, 1972 March 14-19 (Box 26, Folder 28)
    - Washington, D.C., 1972 Feb. 21-23 (Box 26, Folder 29)
    - Phoenix/Los Angeles, 1972 March 6-7 (Box 26, Folder 30)
    - Los Angeles, 1972 Jan. 28 (Box 26, Folder 31)
    - New York/Los Angeles/San Diego, 1971 Oct. 27-30 (Box 26, Folder 32)
    - Salt Lake City, 1971 Nov. 11-12 (Box 26, Folder 33)
    - Los Angeles/Santa Barbara Trip, 1971 Oct. 18-19 (Box 26, Folder 34)
    - New York Trip, 1971 Sept. 20-22 (Box 26, Folder 35)
    - TRIPS Miscellaneous Information, 1969-1971 (Box 26, Folder 36)
    - France and England, 1971 (Box 26, Folder 37)
    - RENO, 1971 May 17 (Box 26, Folder 38)
    - Houston, 1971 Jan. 28 (Box 26, Folder 39)
    - Los Angeles, 1970 Dec. 16-18 (Box 26, Folder 40)
    - Portland, 1970 Nov. 3 (Box 26, Folder 41)
    - Seattle, 1970 Nov. 2 (Box 26, Folder 42)
    - France and England, 1970 (Box 26, Folder 43)
    - Sun Valley, Idaho, 1968-1970 (Box 26, Folder 44)
    - England, 1968-1969 (Box 26, Folder 45)
    - London Expenses, 1968-1969 (Box 26, Folder 46)
    - British Higher Education (Study for The Ford Foundation), 1968-1971 (Box 26, Folder 47)
    - Hong Kong, 1966 Dec. (Box 26, Folder 48)
    - England, 1966 April (Box 26, Folder 49)
    - Japan (Cancelled), 1966 March (Box 26, Folder 50)
    - Europe, 1964 (Box 26, Folder 51)
    - England, 1963 (Box 26, Folder 52)
    - Round the World Miscellaneous, 1960 (Box 26, Folder 53)
    - Round the World Letters from U.S.A., 1960 (Box 26, Folder 54)
    - Round the World -- France, 1960 (Box 26, Folder 55)
    - Round the World -- Italy, 1960 (Box 26, Folder 56)
    - Round the World -- Greece, 1960 (Box 26, Folder 57)
    - Round the World -- Near East, 1960 (Box 26, Folder 58)
    - Round the World -- India, 1960 (Box 26, Folder 59)
    - Round the World -- Thailand, 1960 (Box 26, Folder 60)
    - Round the World -- Hong Kong, 1960 (Box 26, Folder 61)
    - Round the World -- Philippines, 1960 (Box 26, Folder 62)
    - Round the World -- Japan, 1960 (Box 26, Folder 63)
    - Round the World -- Trip Log, 1960 (Box 26, Folder 64)
    - European Trips, 1953, 1957, 1958 (Box 26, Folder 65)
    - Dr. Sterling Houston Trip, 1954 June 4 (Box 26, Folder 66)
    - Stanford Medical Center General, 1969-1984 (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - Minorities at Stanford, 1968, 1971 (Box 27, Folder 2)
    - Miscellaneous, 1968 Oct. 28 (Box 27, Folder 3)
    - Music Department, 1970-1971 (Box 27, Folder 4)
    - New Founders League, 1971-1973 (Box 27, Folder 5)
    - News & Publications, 1978, 1980 (Box 27, Folder 6)
    - Overseas Campuses (General), 1958-1980 (Box 27, Folder 7)
    - Personnel Office, 1969-1984 (Box 27, Folder 8)
    - Physics Department, 1971 Oct. (Box 27, Folder 9)
    - Kenneth S. Pitzer, 1970-1978 (Box 27, Folder 10)
    - Placement Center, 1979-1982 (Box 27, Folder 11)
    - Police Department, 1969, 1976 (Box 27, Folder 12)
    - Political Science, 1970-1976 (Box 27, Folder 13)
    - P.O.W. Letters, 1973 March (Box 27, Folder 14)
    - President's Office (General), 1968-1984 (Box 27, Folder 15)
    - President's Office Donald Kennedy, 1979-1985 (Box 27, Folder 16)
    - President's Office Richard W. Lyman, 1970-1985 (Box 27, Folder 17)
    - Professorships, 1969 (Box 27, Folder 18)
    - Publicity, 1970-1979 (Box 27, Folder 19)
    - Public Events Office, 1969-1981 (Box 27, Folder 20)
    - R.O.T.C., 1966-1973 (Box 27, Folder 21)
    - Registrar's Office, 1981-1985 (Box 27, Folder 22)
    - Religious Studies, 1965-1985 (Box 27, Folder 23)
    - Research, 1972 April 27 (Box 27, Folder 24)
    - Retirement Letters, 1969-1984 (Box 27, Folder 25)
    - Rosters, 1980-1982 (Box 27, Folder 26)
    - Southern California Office, 1970-1985 (Box 27, Folder 27)
    - Stanford Associates, 1969-1985 (Box 27, Folder 28)
    - S.L.A.C., 1971-1982 (Box 27, Folder 29)
    - Stanford Daily, 1973-1974 (Box 27, Folder 30)
    - Study of Education at Stanford, 1968-1970 (Box 27, Folder 31)
    - Taxation, 1969-1974 (Box 27, Folder 32)
    - Undergraduate Division, 1969-1972 (Box 27, Folder 33)
    - University Advisory Committee, 1969-1970 (Box 27, Folder 34)
    - University Relations Office, 1971-1977 (Box 27, Folder 35)
    - Visitors, 1968-1984 (Box 27, Folder 36)
    - Winds of Freedom, 1968-1972 (Box 27, Folder 37)
    - Academic Council/Faculty Senate, 1980 May 30 (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - Academic Information Center, 1970, 1980 (Box 28, Folder 2)
    - Activism (Miscellaneous), 1970 (Box 28, Folder 3)
    - Admissions - General, 1980-1985 (Box 28, Folder 4)
    - Admissions - Special Cases, 1983 (Box 28, Folder 5)
    - A.A.U.P., 1973 (Box 28, Folder 6)
    - Academic Council, 1972-1978 (Box 28, Folder 7)
    - Alumni Associations, circa 1985 (Box 28, Folder 8)
    - Archives, 1968 Nov 19 (Box 28, Folder 9)
    - Art Department, Undated (Box 28, Folder 10)
    - ASSU, 1978-1981 (Box 28, Folder 11)
    - Athletic Department, 1969-1984 (Box 28, Folder 12)
    - Rose Bowl, 1971 (Box 28, Folder 13)
    - Business Affairs Office, 1980 (Box 28, Folder 14)
    - GSB 50th Anniversary Dinner Rick Hyatt House, 1975 Oct 25 (Box 28, Folder 15)
    - Business School, 1969-1984 (Box 28, Folder 16)
    - BYU Decision, 1969-1970 (Box 28, Folder 17)
    - Harry Camp Lectures, 1970 (Box 28, Folder 18)
    - Donald T Carlson, Undated (Box 28, Folder 19)
    - Commencement, 1972-1983 (Box 28, Folder 20)
    - Commitment for Art, 1969 (Box 28, Folder 21)
    - Congratulation Letters, 1969-1984 (Box 28, Folder 22)
    - Controller's Office, 1969-1978 (Box 28, Folder 23)
    - Dean of Student, 1980 (Box 28, Folder 24)
    - Development - Office of, 1981-1985 (Box 28, Folder 25)
    - Earth Science, 1984 (Box 28, Folder 26)
    - School of Education, 1979 (Box 28, Folder 27)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1969-1976 (Box 28, Folder 28)
    - School of Engineering, 1971 (Box 28, Folder 29)
    - Stanford Faculty Club, 1982 (Box 28, Folder 30)
    - Stanford University Faculty Organization, 1983 (Box 28, Folder 31)
    - Food Research Institute, 1970-1976 (Box 28, Folder 32)
    - Foreign Students, 1978 Sept 11 (Box 28, Folder 33)
    - Founders' Day, 1976 (Box 28, Folder 34)
    - The Founding Grant, undated (Box 28, Folder 35)
    - Freshman Seminars, 1969-1973 (Box 28, Folder 36)
    - General Secretary's Office, 1968-1974 (Box 28, Folder 37)
    - Frederic O. Glover, 1976-1985 (Box 28, Folder 38)
    - Hoover Institute, 1969-1984 (Box 28, Folder 39)
    - Hospital, 1974-1975 (Box 28, Folder 40)
    - Housing Advisory Committee, 1968-1972 (Box 28, Folder 41)
    - Humanities and Sciences, 1968-1983 (Box 28, Folder 42)
    - International Studies Visiting Committee, 1975-1977 (Box 28, Folder 43)
    - Law School, 1969-1983 (Box 28, Folder 44)
    - Stanford Law Society of So. California, 1969-1983 (Box 28, Folder 45)
    - Library, 1984 (Box 28, Folder 46)
    - Death Notices: Survivor's Response (Writer Unidentifiable), 1972-1981 (Box 29, Folder 1)
    - Notices of Death (Siv), 1985 (Box 29, Folder 2)
    - A1, 1977-1985 (Box 29, Folder 3)
    - B2, 1971-1984 (Box 29, Folder 4)
    - C3, 1971-1985 (Box 29, Folder 5)
    - D4, 1966-1983 (Box 29, Folder 6)
    - E5, 1969-1983 (Box 29, Folder 7)
    - F6, 1974-1983 (Box 29, Folder 8)
    - G7, 1973-1983 (Box 29, Folder 9)
    - H8, 1971-1984 (Box 29, Folder 10)
    - Garden, 1961-1984 (Box 40, Folder 1)
    - Sterling - 25 Years at Stanford, 1974 (Box 40, Folder 2)
    - Citizenship Materials (Dr. Sterling), 1946-1947 (Box 40, Folder 3)
    - Chautauqua (Memories of Summer 1929), 1974-1979 (Box 40, Folder 4)
    - Security Clearance (Dr. Sterling), 1968-1983 (Box 40, Folder 5)
    - List of Stanford Trustees, 1965-1985 (Box 40, Folder 6)
    - Old Gang Luncheon, 1979-1982 (Box 40, Folder 7)
    - Biographical Sketches: copy for, 1980-1984 (Box 40, Folder 8)
    - Miscellaneous Statements for Publication, 1960-1973 (Box 40, Folder 9)
    - Miscellaneous Scripts for TV and Radio, 1955-1964 (Box 40, Folder 10)
    - Shae & Begg, Limited and Fireman's Fund Insurance Company Combined Directors' Meeting, 1970 March 25 (Box 40, Folder 11)
    - Fire in Office - Inventories, etc., 1968 (Box 40, Folder 12)
    - Sterling Retirement Correspondence, 1967-1968 (Box 40, Folder 13)
    - Sterling Retirement Miscellaneous, 1967-1968 (Box 40, Folder 14)
    - Sterling Retirement UC Dinner - 12 September 1968, 1968 July-Sept. (Box 40, Folder 15)
    - Huntington Library & Art Gallery fliers, financial documents, minutes, correspondence, 1963-1966 (Box 41, Folder 1)
    - Huntington Library(s) & Art Gallery financial documents, minutes, correspondence, 1962-1963 (Box 41, Folder 2)
    - Huntington Library 1961 financial documents, minutes, correspondence, 1960-1961 (Box 41, Folder 3)
    - Huntington Library 1960 (Box 41, Folder 4)
    - Huntington Library 1959 (Jews), 1958-1959 (Box 41, Folder 5)
    - Huntington Library 1958, 1957-1958 (Box 41, Folder 6)
    - Huntington Library 1957 (Sterling) (Box 41, Folder 7)
    - Huntington Library Sterling, 1956 (Box 42, Folder 1)
    - Huntington Library financial documents, correspondence, 1955 (Box 42, Folder 2)
    - Huntington Library and Art Gallery, financial documents, correspondence, news clippings, 1955 (Box 42, Folder 3)
    - Huntington Library financial documents, correspondence, 1944 (Box 42, Folder 4)
  - Alphabetical files
    - A, 1962-1985 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Theodore C. Achilles, 1967-1976 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - James R. Adriance, 1964-1976 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - American Academy of Arts and Sciences, 1967-1981 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - AMICO (The Americas Group), 1967-1976 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - American Historical Association, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 6)